karlhillx@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/khill

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH LEADERSHIP STRENGTHS, LOOKING FOR NEW CHALLENGES

# **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer and Architect with over 25 years of experience in executing the software development lifecycle (SDLC) in agile, consumer-facing environments. Has a demonstrated history of working on complex projects, exceeding customer expectations, and achieving aggressive goals. Built positive relationships across business functions to drive development, increasing functionality, usability, and accessibility of products while reducing design, development, and maintenance costs.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER, NASA, 2017 - Present, Science Systems and Applications, Inc. (SSAI), Greenbelt, MD

- Built an automated content registry application for NASA Earth Observatory that crawls NASA domains to discover new online earth science content enriching internal data and increasing research efficiency by over 50%.
- Overhauled award-winning website, <u>earthobservatory.nasa.gov</u>, a high-traffic site with roughly 1.5 million monthly hits; streamlined site for improved performance and usability.
- Led redevelopment of internal administration systems used by 15 employees, improving functionality and reliability by 20%.
- Authored business requirements for NASA Direct Readout Laboratory application, led requirements elicitation sessions (including requirements analysis), solution assessment and validation, use cases, and interface/functionality mock-ups.

#### LARAVEL DEVELOPER, 2016 – 2017, InformedDNA, St. Petersburg, FL

- Developed and architected a case management application for medical professionals, resulting in better usability, reduced runtime performance by 50% of the previous application, and saving roughly \$35K in UX/UI work.
- Increased use with the new application by more than 35%; eliminated the need for three DB instances using custom APIs.
- Led development of features for the company's CRM system, resulting in increased adoption and accelerated revenues.
- Kept application up to date with the latest technology upgrades to ensure security, including patching and backups.

### SENIOR CONSULTANT, 2012 – 2015, Ticomix, Inc., Washington, DC

- Implemented custom CRM applications for over 20 clients, including VDOT (Virginia Department of Transportation),
   Washington Redskins, and Kastle Systems, providing advanced functionality for new/existing features and increasing sales.
- Reduced defect backlog from hundreds to 25 at launch, improving product quality while maintaining a high customer satisfaction rating and reducing support costs for a top-tier client.

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, 2010 - 2012, Sabre Corporation, Bethesda, MD

- Developed and enhanced applications in a fast-paced environment, meeting performance and reliability for five of the largest global airline, hotel, and travel agency clients (improved customer satisfaction scores by 20%).
- Worked with marketing to drive email and social media advertising, using modeling, resulting in a 15% increase in revenue.
- Mentored three junior developers and new hires, helping them grow professionally (each was promoted within a year).

Additional roles include **Senior Software Engineer** for **Verizon**, **Dante Inc**, **Visitar**, and **Advantage Industries**, plus current volunteer developer positions at **Friendship Place** and **The Renwick Gallery of the Smithsonian American Art Museum**.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Project Management - Rutgers University, Camden, NJ

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science coursework - University of Maryland Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD

Associate of Arts (A.A.), General Studies - Howard Community College, Columbia, MD

#### SKILLS

Laravel, PHP, PHPUnit, TDD, Apache, Tomcat, LAMP, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, MVC, Symfony, Webpack, NPM, OOP, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Git, GitHub/GitLab, Subversion SVN, APIs, REST, JSON, UX/UI, Agile, Scrum, Java, JSF, SugarCRM, WordPress, Drupal, Apache Nutch, ElasticSearch, AWS (Amazon Web Services), Atlassian Suite: (JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket), Composer, Bash & Shell scripting